SARAH CAHILL

4/289 Arden St, Coogee 2034, NSW

Email: scahill03@hotmail.com Tel: 0401810746

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarah-cahill-2b67b212/

High-achieving, target-orientated general manager with extensive experience in retailing, with a background in marketing and category management. Thorough, reliable and detail-conscious individual who believes in getting things done right first time, and a natural leader. Excellent interpersonal, influencing and communication and presentation skills with an organised approach.

Education & Qualifications	
Diploma in Information Technology Academy of Information Technology	2021 - ongoing
Professional Diploma in Digital Marketing Digital Marketing Institute	2019 – 2020
Master of Marketing Monash University	2012 – 2018
Bachelor of Arts – major in Sociology University of New South Wales	1999 – 2001
Professional Experience	
General Manager – Marketing	2016 – 2020

General manager of marketing department, with responsibility for all publicity, event marketing, instore
marketing, including producing monthly campaigns with digital and instore assets across dual brands. Total
store count was 100+.

Australian Geographic, The Co-op

- Development of strategic partnerships, including work on the membership value proposition and local area marketing opportunities.
- Developing and managing business plans across the OTC, online and B2B sales channels. Extensive involvement in the Co-op and AG websites, including EDMs, online merchandising and bespoke web campaigns.
- Launch of new Australian Geographic website, including developing brief, setting overall strategies and working with digital design agency. Some responsibility for eCommerce, including marketing activities and website optimisation. Skills in social media, Mail Chimp and Emarsys.
- Designing event marketing program in order to drive sales, promote customer engagement and build brand awareness.
- Creating merchandising guidelines and instructing stores on design and layout, in-store branding and POS.
 Basic skills in Photoshop and InDesign.
- Negotiating all trading terms, promotional support, inventory management, building and maintenance of trading partnerships.
- Part of executive leadership team, senior member of management team, including extensive presenting to board.

- Australian Geographic/Curious Planet nominated for Customer Service Team of the year in 2018, 2019 and 2020 for Inside Retail Awards, and for Omnichannel Retailer of the Year and CX experience at the National Retail Awards in 2019.
- Responsibility for organising and running annual three day store conference, with attendance of 200+ people.
- Managing team including a senior buyer, inventory manager, inventory planner, marketing and campaign planner and assistant.

Senior Buyer WHSmith Australia

2016 - 2016

- Developed and managed range of all Books, Magazines and Newspapers, with responsibility for sales, gross margin and inventory for all WHSmith, Supanews and Fresh + (thirty stores in total), with a \$20m+ portfolio.
- Direct reports of two buyers who were responsible for buying Confectionery, Drinks, Fresh Food, Telcoms, Tobacco and Lottery.
- Setting strategic marketing direction within the categories, and creating profitable promotional plans, which have led to increased market share and sales within Book and Magazine categories. The Books category saw 20% YOY growth.
- Reinvigoration of marketing plan for both categories, exceeding bullish supplier income targets.
- Completing regular exception reporting and analysis for customer, product, suppliers, competition and marketing, utilising this in optimisation of supply chain operations.
- Management of two buyers and a buying assistant.

Buyer Target Australia

2014 - 2015

- Total buying responsibility for Book and Magazine categories Target and Target Country (over 300 stores in total), with a \$60m+ portfolio.
- Developed and delivered strategic direction and tactical merchandise plans, incorporating business direction and market trends for both categories. The books category saw unprecedented sales growth, with 18% YOY growth in the first year, and 30% YOY growth the second year.
- Participation in weekly catalogues with circulation of over six million, including a standalone ten page book catalogue twice a year.
- Relationship building with suppliers, including trading terms and bringing new suppliers on board.
- Management of allocations analyst and buying assistant.

Category Manager LS Travel Retail, Australia

2011 - 2013

- Category management of books and multimedia departments for Newslink, Relay and Watermark stores, for Australia and New Zealand (sixty stores in total), with a \$25m+ portfolio.
- Reviewing new and existing products, approval of product range for each store and stock levels. Ensured profitability of books category within greater business plan, for both Australia and New Zealand.
- Acted as key contact within Marketing department for Planning and Development department, managing new store and refurbishments.
- Introduced e Readers into stores providing a digital solution for travellers.
- Overseeing of introduction of a content based app into stores.
- Management of a buyer, inventory manager and buying assistant.

National Buyer ABC, Australia 2010 - 2011

- Full responsibility and accountability for all buying and merchandising of Books, Audio, Magazine, Calendars & Diary categories for ABC Shops and ABC online (55 stores in total), with a \$20m+ portfolio.
- Liaising with broader ABC Commercial team in regards to product development, ensuring consistency of brand message and product offer.
- Participating in up to ten catalogues a year, and developing full catalogue briefs for seasonal bookgift guides; marketing strategy on catalogue look, choosing titles and writing copy, negotiating marking spend, full sales analysis on results and profitability.
- Working with buyers for other product areas, in order to present a coherent product offer to the customer using extensive cross merchandising and capitalising on market trends.

Buyer Borders, UK

2006 - 2009

- Buying roles included Assistant Airports Buyer, then promoted to Airports Buyer and Non Fiction buyer.
 Responsibility for Borders and Books Etc stores, and Borders Online (over 50 stores in total). Largest portfolio managed was £35m+.
- Delivering optimum sales, margin, income, and delivering income targets and stock turn in designated areas. Owning the development and implementation of a coherent product offer strategy / category plan to optimise the core Borders business.
- Identifying opportunities for exclusives, value-added and new product development and working with publishers to realise them.

Buyer Blackwell's Bookshop, Edinburgh

2003 - 2006

- Complete buying responsibility of the Children's section in the bookshop.
- Extensive involvement in the Edinburgh Book Festival.
- Guest lecturer at Edinburgh University on Children's books to first year education students.

Marketing Assistant Harlequin Enterprises, Australia

2001 - 2003

• Assistant duties in the direct marketing department.

Referees

Previous employment references available on request.